JAMES ROONEY

Unit 103, 1919 West 8th Avenue, Vancouver, V6J 1W2 • james.rooney@hotmail.co.uk • jamespatrickrooney.com 778 2281985

PROFILE

A sales and marketing specialist with a variety of experience in the legal, e-commerce, mobile app, online gaming and consumer packaged goods industries. Specializes in maximizing business growth through analysis, strong communication skills and an ability to develop strong relationships with multiple stakeholders

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

Digital Marketing Professional Program

Red Academy, Vancouver, BC

Relevant Courses: Content Marketing, Email Marketing, Inbound Marketing, SEM

Certifications: Google Analytics, Google Adwords

Master of Business Administration, Business Innovation Track

2014

2016

Sauder School of Business, UBC, Vancouver, BC

Relevant Courses: Brand Management, Consumer Behavior, Marketing Research

Completion of the Brand Management Mentorship program

Bachelor of Laws 2006

The University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Digital Marketing Consultant

Blast Ramp, Vancouver, BC

July 2016

Formulated an Inbound Marketing strategy to nurture leads through to live demo signup

My Green Space, Vancouver, BC

June 2016 Created Mobile App launch strategy to reach 3000 downloads over 1 month campaign

Circle Craft. Vancouver. BC May 2016

Developed a holiday marketing campaign to increase site traffic by 25% for the e-commerce store

Sales Executive

Lazymeal, Canada, Vancouver, BC

August 2015 – March 2016

Responsible for outbound sales at online food ordering startup. Increased partners by 15% in 7 months

Sales Leadership Development Program

March 2014-May 2015

PepsiCo Canada, Vancouver, BC

- Maximized business growth for the Unit by 1.7% versus last year, in a declining market, by providing exceptional customer service to large, mid and small format accounts, including Wal Mart, IGA, Save On Foods, Shoppers Drug Mart and Shell
- Executed national and regional promotions by successfully placing incremental marketing equipment such as displays and racks in key accounts, resulting in 78% success rate for placing innovation products

Marketing Strategy & Business Development Intern

IgnitePlay, Canada, Vancouver, BC

June

August 2013

- Forecasted to increase partnerships by 25% and subscribers by 50% by the end of 2013 by devising a partnership & brand ambassador strategy aimed at leveraging IgnitePlay's most passionate players while targeting female millennials.
- Created a partner specific brand awareness and product purchase scheme with aim of increasing revenue by 20% year on year by researching a suitable partner company to collaborate with and determining key areas of mutual interest

Marketing Manager

- Generated £245,000 in revenue with the introduction of 83 new cases while managing a five-person marketing team and motivating them to be creative to produce new income streams
- Improved brand recognition in geographic areas outside the firm's traditional strongholds by focusing on localized consumer preferences and aligning brand with those preferences, resulting in a 1000% increase in cases
- Assisted in creating and executing strategy for allocating a £1 million budget for radio and internet marketing resulting in 2000 new cases

Solicitor September 2010 – May 2011

 Negotiated client compensation in excess of £150,000 by appealing to the personal interests of both clients and insurers thereby influencing them to settle on mutually agreeable terms

Trainee Solicitor.

EAD Solicitors LLP, Liverpool, UK

September 2008 – August 2010

• Developed ability to influence clients and opponents and prioritize projects, through the successful participation in 20 high-value legal cases

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

UBC Sustainability Fund

Jan - June 2013

• Co – Created a UBC Sustainability Fund with 3 other MBA students by devising a go to market plan that was created through analyzing 10 similar funds across North America

INTERESTS

Buying investment grade wine, classical, country and western music, playing golf (13 handicap) Adrenaline junky – shark cage diver, sky diver, bungy jumper and rapids rider